<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Light Wallets on Zcash Warp Sync</title><link>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/</link><description>Recent content in Light Wallets on Zcash Warp Sync</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Purpose</title><link>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/purpose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/purpose/</guid><description>The main purpose of a Light Wallet or any wallet for that matter is to provide:
the capability to receive funds, the capability to send funds, and display the funds available In addition, Light Wallet should be less resource-demanding than regular wallets. In the past, the latter term has been used to refer to full nodes.
Full node wallets download the entire blockchain and keep a fairly extensive representation of the data within.</description></item><item><title>Privacy</title><link>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/privacy/</guid><description>Non-private coins make up the vast majority of wallets. Almost all cryptocurrency users rely on them. As a result, they have come to expect a certain level of functionality and speed.
But private coins present significant challenges that non-private coins do not have. Because the content of the blockchain is hidden or encrypted, third party services cannot index the transactions and maintain address balances in advance.
Imagine having a dictionary where every word and definition is redacted.</description></item><item><title>UTXO Model</title><link>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/utxo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/utxo/</guid><description>Zcash is a Blockchain that uses the UTXO model first introduced in Bitcoin.
UTXO Initially, every account/address has an empty balance. The only way to get coins into an account is through a transaction (TX).
Transactions take inputs and produce outputs. Except for the mining transaction called the coinbase transaction, every transaction has inputs that fund the outputs.
We&amp;rsquo;ll not consider mining or minting and therefore we&amp;rsquo;ll ignore the coinbase transaction.</description></item><item><title>Scan / Sync</title><link>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/scan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/scan/</guid><description>Scanning the blockchain can be done in several ways. Ultimately they all achieve the same goal:
Determine which notes you received, ie adding incoming funds, Cross-out the notes you spent, ie substracting outgoing funds, And finally, allowing you to spend your UTXO. The first two bullet points are typical of any UTXO based cryptocurrency wallet, but the last bullet point may be unusual.
Once the blockchain scan finishes, your wallet is said to be synchronized.</description></item><item><title>Reorganization</title><link>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/reorg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/reorg/</guid><description>Reorganizations happen when several miners submit different blocks at the same height.
It is a rare occurence but it happens.
For example, if you have the following situation:
Miner A submits block 1001 after block 1000 Miner B submits a different block 1001 Miner C submits a block 1002 based on miner B&amp;rsquo;s block 1001 Now we have two chains that deviate at block 1000:
one built from Miner A&amp;rsquo;s block 1001 the other from Miner B&amp;rsquo;s block 1001 and Miner C&amp;rsquo;s 1002 Since nodes cannot determine a-priori which chains will get longer after seeing block 1001, some of them first follow Miner A while others follow Miner B.</description></item></channel></rss>