<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Light Wallets on Zcash Warp Sync</title><link>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/</link><description>Recent content in Light Wallets on Zcash Warp Sync</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Purpose</title><link>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/purpose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/purpose/</guid><description>The main purpose of a Light Wallet or any wallet for that matter is to provide:
the capability to receive funds, the capability to send funds, and display the funds available In addition, Light Wallet should be less resource-demanding than regular wallets. In the past, the latter term has been used to refer to full nodes.
Full node wallets download the entire blockchain and keep a fairly extensive representation of the data within.</description></item><item><title>Privacy</title><link>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/privacy/</guid><description>Non-private coins make up the vast majority of wallets. Almost all cryptocurrency users rely on them. As a result, they have come to expect a certain level of functionality and speed.
But private coins present significant challenges that non-private coins do not have. Because the content of the blockchain is hidden or encrypted, third party services cannot index the transactions and maintain address balances in advance.
Imagine having a dictionary where every word and definition is redacted.</description></item><item><title>UTXO Model</title><link>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/utxo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/light_wallet/utxo/</guid><description>Zcash is a Blockchain that uses the UTXO model first introduced in Bitcoin.
UTXO Initially, every account/address has an empty balance. The only way to get coins into an account is through a transaction (TX).
Transactions take inputs and produce outputs. Except for the mining transaction called the coinbase transaction, every transaction has inputs that fund the outputs.
We&amp;rsquo;ll not consider mining or minting and therefore we&amp;rsquo;ll ignore the coinbase transaction.</description></item></channel></rss>