<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tasks on Zcash Warp Sync</title><link>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/execution_model/tasks/</link><description>Recent content in Tasks on Zcash Warp Sync</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/execution_model/tasks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Download</title><link>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/execution_model/tasks/download/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/execution_model/tasks/download/</guid><description>This task consists of retrieving Compact Blocks from the server and sending them downstream to the other tasks.
Lightwalletd offers a streaming interface that allows us to retrieve a range of blocks without blocking.
The start height is our latest synchronization height + 1. The end height is the latest block. The range can potentially be very large, but we don&amp;rsquo;t buffer more than a chunk of blocks and therefore can process large ranges.</description></item><item><title>Decrypt</title><link>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/execution_model/tasks/decrypt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/execution_model/tasks/decrypt/</guid><description>One of the major tasks in terms of computation is trial decryption.
Every output note (EPK, CIPHERTEXT, CMU) needs to be trial decrypted with every account Incoming Viewing Key (IVK).
There are currently more than 20 million notes (and it increases). If you have 2 accounts, it means having to trial decrypt 40 million times.
Typically, one trial decryption takes ~1 ms (the exact time depends on your CPU). Therefore trial decryption can make up for a substantial portion of the synchronization.</description></item><item><title>Witnesses</title><link>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/execution_model/tasks/witnesses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/execution_model/tasks/witnesses/</guid><description>Note Commitments When someone makes a transactions and therefore creates output notes, they are encrypted. Even when they are spent, notes are not revealed because that would also give the transaction that created them.
In fact, we could imagine a scheme where the notes are not stored in the blockchain but only the zk proofs. Of course, it implies that clients have another way to retrieve the encrypted output if they don&amp;rsquo;t store it themselves.</description></item><item><title>Pipeline</title><link>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/execution_model/tasks/pipeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hhanh00.github.io/zcash-sync/execution_model/tasks/pipeline/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>